A Finding Aid to the Milton Wolf Brown Papers, 1908-1998, in the Archives of American Art AAA.browmilt
Archives of American Art
- Research Files, circa 1930s-1986; Series 7; (Boxes 16-19; 3.0 linear feet)
  - Architecture Subject Files (Box 16)
    - McKim, Mead, and White, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - Richard Meier, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 35)
    - Mies van der Rohe, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 36)
    - Miscellaneous, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 37)
    - Richard Neutra, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 38)
    - New Building Types: Shopping Center, Airport, Factory, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 39)
    - New York, undated (Box 16, Folder 40)
    - I.M. Pei, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 41)
    - Prairie School, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 42)
    - Kevin Roche and John Dinkeloo, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 43)
    - Paul Rudolph, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 44)
    - Eero and Eliel Saarinen, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 45)
    - Rudolph Schindler, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 46)
    - Shreve, Lamb and Harmon, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 47)
    - Skidmore, Owings, and Merrill, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 48)
    - Edward Durrell Stone, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 49)
    - Louis Sullivan, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 50)
    - Robert Venturi, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 51)
    - Frank Lloyd Wright, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 52)
    - Henry Wright, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 53)
  - Armor, undated (Box 16, Folder 54)
  - Art and Archaeology, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 55)
  - Art Nouveau, circa 1964-1978 (Box 16, Folder 56)
  - Art History Theory, 1980s (Box 16, Folder 57)
  - Bergson, Henri, circa 1980s (Box 16, Folder 58)
  - Bibliographies, circa 1930s-1980s (Box 16, Folder 59)
  - Bingham (George Caleb), undated (Box 16, Folder 60)
  - Biographies of Artists, undated; (2 of 4 folders) (Box 16, Folder 61-62)
  - Biographies of Artists, undated; (2 of 4 folders) (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
  - Botticelli, circa 1955-1957 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Byzantine Greece, 1963, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Chateaux, Cathedrals, and Caves, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Contemporary Art, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Copley, 1956, undated (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Costume, 1942, undated (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Denmark, 1960, undated (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Excursions from Paris, undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Fifteenth Century, undated (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Florence, undated; (3 folders) (Box 17, Folder 12-14)
  - France, undated (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - French Colonial, undated (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Gagnini, Antonello, circa 1968 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Gardens and Parks, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Greek Revival Architecture, undated (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - History, Background, undated (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Istanbul, undated (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Italian Architecture, undated (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Italian Renaissance Painting, undated (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Italy, circa 1953 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Lalique, undated (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Languedoc and Provence, 1957-1963 (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - London, undated (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Madrid, 1962, undated (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Medieval, circa 1940s (Box 17, Folder 29-31)
  - Medieval Iconography, undated (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - Mexico, undated (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - Modernists, undated (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - Modern Sculpture, undated (Box 17, Folder 35)
  - Murals, Section of Fine Arts, undated (Box 17, Folder 36)
  - New York, undated; (2 folders) (Box 17, Folder 37-38)
  - Nineteenth and Twentieth Century Architecture, undated (Box 17, Folder 39)
  - Paintings, 1952-1960, undated; (2 folders) (Box 17, Folder 40-41)
  - Painting, American, 1789-1850, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Painting, American, 1850-1900, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Painting, American, 1900s, circa 1952-1956; (3 folders) (Box 18, Folder 3-5)
  - Painting, American, Colonial, undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Painting, American, General, circa 1951-1958 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Painting, American, Taste, undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Painting, American, Twentieth Century, Modernism from 1913, undated; (2 folders) (Box 18, Folder 9-10)
  - Painting, Fifteenth Century, Italy, 1944, undated; (2 folders) (Box 18, Folder 11-12)
  - Painting, Fifteenth Century, Italy, Florence, undated (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Painting, Fifteenth Century, North, circa 1944-1957 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Paris, 1963, undated (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Patronage and Taste, undated (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Railroad Stations, undated (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Revisionism in Art History, circa 1987 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Rome, circa 1951-1986; (2 folders) (Box 18, Folder 19-20)
  - Rome, Excursions, undated (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Science, undated (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Sculpture, undated (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Sculpture, American, undated; (3 folders) (Box 18, Folder 24-26)
  - Sicily, circa 1957-1964 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Sixteenth Century, undated (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Social (Revolutionary) Art, circa 1940s, undated (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Spain, circa 1948-1964; (3 folders) (Box 18, Folder 30-32)
  - Spanish Colonial, undated (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Spanish Painting, undated (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - Straus Collection, undated (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - Structuralism and Semiotics, circa 1950s-1980s; (3 folders) (Box 18, Folder 36-38)
  - Twentieth Century American Architecture, undated (Box 18, Folder 39)
  - U. S. S. R., undated (Box 18, Folder 40)
  - Venice, undated (Box 18, Folder 41)
  - Western Artists, undated (Box 18, Folder 42)
  - Whistler, undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Yugoslavia, 1965 (Box 19, Folder 2)
- Teaching Files, circa 1946-1993; Series 8; (Boxes 19-21; 2.0 linear feet)
  This series contains Milton Brown's teaching files for his work at several academic institutions. Included are course materials such as lecture notes, syllabi, and class lists as well as other related records such as scattered correspondence, examinations, and faculty memos and reports from his tenure at the City University of New York and Brooklyn College. Additional files document his teaching positions at Hebrew University and the Center for Advanced Study in the Visual Arts. This series also includes files of recommendation requests from students and writings by students.
  - Brooklyn College, Course Materials, 1959, undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Brooklyn College, Miscellaneous Records, circa 1960-1970 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - City University of New York (Box 19)
    - Art Nouveau Workshop, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Iconography of Modern Art, undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous Records, 1972-1988; (2 folders) (Box 19, Folder 7-8)
    - Ph.D. Program in Art History Expansion, 1988-1989 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Photorealism Seminar, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Realism in American Painting, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Seminar: Art Nouveau, circa 1973, 1989; (2 folders) (Box 19, Folder 12-13)
    - Symposium in Honor of Professor Milton W. Brown, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Course Materials, "Design 1.1 and 1.2,", circa 1955 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Examinations, 1946-1966 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Hebrew University of Jerusalem, 1980-1985; (2 folders) (Box 19, Folder 17-18)
  - Institute of Fine Arts, Seminar: First Wave of Modernism, 1981-1982 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Lecture Materials, circa 1940s-1970s (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - National Gallery of Art Center for Advanced Study in the Visual Arts, 1987-1990; (3 folders) (Box 19, Folder 21-23)
  - New York University, American Studies Examinations, 1990-1993 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Reading List, "Aspects of Precisionism and Realism in the United States,", undated (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Recommendation Requests, circa 1970s-1990s; (5 folders) (Box 19, Folder 26-30)
  - Selection Committee, Goodson Symposium on American Art, 1979-1980 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Slide Lists, 1954, undated (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Teaching Material from Other Academic Institutions, circa 1945-1980s (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Writings by Students, 1952-1993; (19 folders) (Box 20, Folder 4-22)
  - Writings by Students, 1952-1993 (Box 21, Folder 1)
- Organization Files, 1959-1995; Series 9; (Boxes 21-22; 1.3 linear feet)
  This series includes files maintained by Milton Brown for organizations in which he participated. For most of these organizations he either served as a member or project advisor. Of note are his participation as a member of the Board of Trustees for the Archives of American Art and his service on various committees for the Century Association and the College Art Association. Files may include correspondence, reports, planning documents, agendas, meeting minutes, and conference and event materials.
  - Adirondack Mountain Club, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Archives of American Art (Box 21)
    - Advisory Committee, 1968-1974, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Board of Trustees, 1988-circa 1986 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1962-1996 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Printed Material, circa 1962-1988 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Reports, 1968-1972 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Search Committee, 1989-1990 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - ArtsAmerica, Inc., 1987-1991 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Bollingen Foundation, 1959-1960 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Century Association (Box 21)
    - Committee on House Art, 1981-1985; (2 folders) (Box 21, Folder 11-12)
    - Correspondence, 1978, 1982-1992 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Exhibition Committee, 1983-1988 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Nominations, 1979-1981; (2 folders) (Box 21, Folder 15-16)
    - Printed Material, circa 1973-1977 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - College Art Association, 1950-1978; (5 folders) (Box 21, Folder 18-22)
  - College Art Association, Committee on Graduate Education in Art History, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - District 1199 Cultural Center, Inc., 1979 (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Dunlap Society, 1979-1982 (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Friends of the Catalogue Raisonne, 1985-1987 (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - Henry Street Settlement, 1963 (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - Italian Encyclopedia Institute, 1986-1989 (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - James Marston Fitch Charitable Trust, 1988-1990 (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - Library of American Art, undated (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - Long Island University, Trustee Awards for Scholarly Achievement, 1987-1989 (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art, Deaccessioning Controversy, 1972-1973 (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art, Fine Arts Center Controversy, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - National Museum of American Art, Professional Appraisal and Evaluation Committee, 1988-1990 (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - Odessa Films, 1991-1992 (Box 21, Folder 35)
  - Phi Beta Kappa, 1986-1988; (2 folders) (Box 21, Folder 36-37)
  - Program for Art on Film, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 38)
  - Smithsonian Council, 1976-1985; (3 of 5 folders) (Box 21, Folder 39-41)
  - Smithsonian Council, 1976-1985; (2 of 5 folders) (Box 22, Folder 1-2)
  - Society of Architectural Historians, 1952, 1971, 1983; (3 folders) (Box 22, Folder 3-5)
  - Victorian Society, 1970-1977 (Box 22, Folder 6)
- Printed Material, 1925-1990s; Series 10; (Boxes 22-24, 26, 27; 3.2 linear feet)
  Printed material consists primarily of exhibition announcements and invitations sent to Milton Brown, journals and newsletters from various art organizations, and magazine articles collected by Brown during his career as an art historian. Also found are brochures, conference programs, catalogs, press releases, and news clippings mostly related to Brown's professional activities.
  Files are arranged alphabetically by type of printed material.
  - Advertisement Brochures, undated (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Appointment Calendar (No written entries), 1977 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Catalogs, "Mason Fine Prints,", 1974-1978 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Conference Programs, 1952-1987 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, circa 1960s-1990s; (10 folders) (Box 22, Folder 11-20)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, circa 1960s-1990s; (13 folders) (Box 23, Folder 1-13)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, circa 1940-1983 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Guide, National Gallery of Art, undated (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Journal, Index of Twentieth Century Artists, 1933-1937; (3 folders) (Box 23, Folder 16-18)
  - Journal, The Pragmatist in Art, 1964-1978 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Journal, Reality, 1953-1954 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Magazines, 1958, 1925-1977; (2 folders) (Box 24, Folder 3-4)
  - Magazine Articles, Clippings and Reprints, 1932-1990s, undated; (11 folders) (Box 24, Folder 5-15)
  - "Manipulart,", 1966 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Material regarding Jack Levine Film, 1985-1986 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Newsletters, ARC Directions, 1967, circa 1970 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Newsletters, A. H. A. A., 1979-1984 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Newsletters, CAA, 1976-1983 (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Newsletters, Federal Art Patronage Notes, 1975-1981 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Newsletters, Graduate School News Report, 1981-1984 (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Newsletters, Historic Landmarks News, 1970-1972 (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Newsletters, IFA Alumni Newsletter, 1966-1990 (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - Newsletters, MOMA Members Newsletter, 1968-1970 (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Newsletters, The Victorian Society in America, 1967-1986; (2 folders) (Box 26, Folder 1-2)
  - Newsletters, Miscellaneous, 1940-1994; (2 folders) (Box 26, Folder 3-4)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1935-1991, undated; (2 folders) (Box 26, Folder 5-6)
  - Press Releases, 1960s-1980s (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Travel Brochures, circa 1960s-1990 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Travel Brochures, circa 1960s-1990 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, circa 1960s-1980s; (2 folders) (Box 27, Folder 2-3)
- Photographs, circa 1956-1990s; Series 11; (Boxes 25, 27; 0.2 linear feet)
  This series contains scattered photographs, including 9 photographs of Milton Brown, photographs of artist Jan Cox, and publicity photographs of the actress Maureen Stapleton. Also found are photographs of works of art, including several of works by Jacob Lawrence. Researchers should note that additional photographs may be found within Series 4.2: Book Projects and Series 6: Exhibition Files.
  - Milton Wolf Brown, circa 1960s-1990s (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Milton Wolf Brown, circa 1960s-1990s (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Jan Cox, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Maureen Stapleton, circa 1976 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - San Francisco, circa 1960s (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Unidentified Snapshots, circa 1990s (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Artwork by Lois Dodd, 1969-1979 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Artwork by Arthur Dove (Transparencies), undated (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Artwork by Jacob Lawrence, circa 1974 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Artwork by Jacob Lawrence, "Struggle Series,", circa 1956 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Artwork, Miscellaneous, 1976, undated (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Artwork, Miscellaneous Slides and Transparencies, undated (Box 27, Folder 14)